! don't know about you, it's just too hot today, isn't it?
大家都感觉到吧 今天热死了
And it’s going to get even worse. Temperatures up in the mid-30s Celsius...
而且明天会更热 气温会升到摄氏三十冯度
...that's the mid-90s Fahrenheit, tomorrow, maybe even hitting 100.
就是桂氏九十冯度 也许会破百
So, please, remember to cover up and stay cool...
请记得防电、保持清刺
...with the hottest hits on your FM dial.
继续收获我们所播出 最热门的音乐
Come on, guys, time to go home.
来吧，该回家了
Come on, love, off you get.
宝忠，下来
-Do we have to? -Yes, we do.
-一定要回家吗? -当然唆
V'll make you your favorite dinner to compensate.
我会做你最党的菜补倘你
He squealed like a pig, didn’t he?
他像猪一样尖叫
Yeah, brilliant punch, Big D. Did you see his face?
打得好，思老大，超棒的
Hey, Big D.
嘿，束老大
Beat up another 10-year-old?
又在欺负小孩了吗?
-This one deserved it. -Yeah.
-这小鬼活该 -是啊
-Five against one, very brave. -Well, you're one to talk.
-五个打一个，好勇敢哦 -你还敢说我?
Moaning in your sleep every night? At least I'm not afraid of my pillow.
你每晚睡觉都会哀哀叫 至少我不会怕我的枕头
"Don't kill Cedric.”
“不要杀西追7
Who's Cedric, your boyfriend?
西追是谁? 你男友吗?
-Shut up. -"He’s going to kill me, Mum.”
-闭嘴 -“妈，他要杀我“
Where is your mum?
你姻在哪里了
Where is your mum, Potter?
你姻在哪里呀，波特?
She dead?
她死了邑?
Is she dead?
她是不是死了?
Is she a dead Pott--?
她肯定插了…
-Dudley. -Dudley, let’s go.
-过力 -加力，我们走吧
-What’'s going on? -What are you doing?
-怎庆回事? -你在搞什么鬼?
-I'm not doing anything. -We're getting out of here, Dudley.
-我什么也没做 -来吧，速力，快走
Come on, Dudley, hurry up.
速力，快跑!
Expecto Patronum.
疾疾，访法现身 !
Mrs. Figg.
费太太
Don't put away your wand, Harry.
抢起魔杖，哈利
They might come back.
他们可能会回来
Dementors in Little Whinging, whatever next?
催狂魔间入小惠因区 接下来呢?
-Whole world’s gone topsy-turvy. -l don’t understand. How do you know--?
-全世界都会一转乱 -我不懂，炼怎订会知道…
Dumbledore asked me to keep an eye on you.
如不利多要我 注意你的安全
Dumbledore asked you? You know Dumbledore?
好不利多? 你认识如不利多?
After You-Know-Who killed that poor Diggory boy last year...
那个人去年 负了可情的迪哥里
...did you expect him to let you go wandering on your own?
你以为他会让你 一个人在外面乱晃吗 ?
Good Lord, boy. They told me you were intelligent.
拜旗，他们还说你很陷明
Now, get inside and stay there.
好了，快进去吧，别出门
Expect someone will be in touch soon. Whatever happens, don't leave the house.
很快就会有人来找你 不管怎样都别出门
it is hot. That's right, hot everywhere.
真是酷热
There's sweat. There's stifling.
各地气候都又混又网热…
Diddykins?
小达速?
Is that you?
是你吧?
Duddy. Vernon, come quick.
威农，快来
We're going to have to take him to a hospital.
我们得把他送到获院
Who did this to you, boy?
这是谁干的好事?
Happy, are we, now?
好了，现在你高和则了吧?
You've finally done it. You've finally driven him loopy.
这下可好 你终於把他融瘦了
Vernon, don’t say that.
威农，别说这种话
Well, just look at him, Petunia. Our boy has gone yumpy.
看看他，佩妮 我们的儿子中邪了
I've reached my limit, do you hear?
我受不了你了，匠到没?
This is the last I'm gonna take of you and your nonsense.
我不能再忍受 你的诡相行径了
-Dear Mr. Potter. -What?
-亲爱的波特先生 -什么?
The Ministry has received intelligence that at 6:23 this evening...
魔法部接获情报 今天傍晚六点二十三分
...you performed the Patronus Charm in the presence of a Muggle.
你当著一个硫丰的面 施展访法咒
As a clear violation...
这征行为最重这反…
...of the Decree for the Reasonable Restriction of Underage Sorcery...
未成年魔法合理使用限制法规
..-you are hereby expelled...
堆格革兹魔法与巫入学校…
...from Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry.
因此决定开除你的学籍
Hoping you are well, Mafalda Hopkirk.
祝你安好，玛法如霍克克
Justice.
老天有了眼
He’s not very well.
他不太舒服
Sorry, Hedwig.
对不起，嘿美
Very clean, these Muggles.
这些碎瓜还满乾潭的嘛
-Tonks, for God's sake. -Unnatural.
-东施，和拜旗好不好 -太不正常了
Professor Moody.
穆地教授
-What are you doing here? -Rescuing you, of course.
-你怎记会来这和里 ? -当然是来救你啊
But where are we going? The letter said I've been expelled.
我们要去哪儿 ? 我被学校开除了
You haven't been. Not yet. Kingsley, you take point.
没有，没那广快 金利，你解释
But the letter said--
可是那封信说…
Dumbledore persuaded the minister to suspend your expulsion...
如不利多 说服魔法部者缓执行
-...pending a formal hearing. -A hearing?
-直到正式区证会举行 -蓝证会?
Don't worry. We'll explain everything when we get back to headquarters.
别提心，回总部再跟你说清楚
Not here, Nymphadora.
别乱说话，小仙女
Don't call me Nymphadora.
不要叫我小仙女
Stay in formation, everyone. Don’t break ranks if one of us is killed.
大家排好飞行队形 就算有人被条也不可有队
Come on, you, around the corner.
你 ! 过来! 转角的那个 !
Come on.
来吧
In you go, son.
进去吧，和孩子
There've been no sightings.
没人看到
No deaths. No proof.
没人死，没有证据
He almost killed Harry. If that isn’t proof enough....
他差点负了哈利就是证据
Yes, but guarding you-know-what is the most important....
话是没错，不过呢… 最重要的是对付那个人
We must trust Dumbledore on this.
我们必须信任如不利多
Was he able to protect Harry last year? Well, tonight I say it’s time to take action.
他去年有保访好哈利吗? 我认为我们应该探取行动了
Cornelius Fudge is a politician first and a wizard second.
夫子只在乎政治 对他来说，巫师身分是其次
-His instinct would be to ignore it-- -Keep your voices down.
-他根本就不会管这件事 -大家小声点
He’s getting stronger and stronger by the minute. We have to act now.
那个人的力量盒来念强 我们一定要马上行动
-Harry. -Mrs. Weasley.
-哈利 -本斯理太太
Heavens, you're all right.
感谢老天，你没事
Bit peaky, but I’m afraid dinner will wait until after the meeting's finished.
有点恬迟 不过会议结束才能吃晚餐
Nope. No time to explain. Straight upstairs, first door on the left.
别问，我没时间解释 你先上楼，左转第一道门
Yeah.
对了
Mudblood, werewolves, traitors, thieves.
硫种、狼人人、叛徒
If my poor mistress knew the scum they let into her house...
还有小偷，如果女主人 知道这些人渣来她家…
...what would she say to old Kreacher?
会跟我怪角说什么呢?
Oh, the shame.
真是可取
-Freaks. -There, there, mistress.
-怪胎 -别生气，女主人
Scum of the earth. Not like it was in the days of my fathers.
低级的人渣，真是世风日下
Kreacher is here.
我怪角永于都会在
Oh, Harry.
哈利
Are you all right? We overheard them talking about the Dementor attack.
你没事吧? 我们偷肌到催狂魔攻击的事
-You must tell us everything. -Let the man breathe, Hermione.
-快告诉我们经过 -先让他喘口气吧，妙最
And this hearing at the Ministry. It’s just outrageous.
还有魔法部区证会 太过分了
I've looked it up. They simply can't expel you.
我查过，他们不能开除你
-It'’s completely unfair. -Yeah.
-太不公平了 -没错
There's a lot of that going round at the moment.
外面发生了很多事情
So, what is this place?
这是什么地方?
-It's headquarters. -Of the Order of the Phoenix.
-这壬是总部 -凤凰会的总部
It's a secret society.
风凰会是个秘密社转
Dumbledore formed it back when they fought You-Know-Who.
如不利多当年 对抗那个人的时候创立的
Couldn't have put any of this in a letter, 1 suppose?
你们不能写信告诉我，对吧?
I've gone all summer without a scrap of news.
整个署假都没你们的消息
We wanted to write, mate. Really, we did.
我们很想写信 真的，不驴你
-Only.... -Only what?
-只是… -只是什么?
Only Dumbledore made us swear not to tell you anything.
好不利多要我们发将 不能告诉你
Dumbledore said that?
好不利多这广说?
But why would he keep me in the dark? Maybe I could help.
他堤嘛旺著我? 也许我能帮忙
I'm the one who saw Voldemort return...
娃竟是我看到 伏地魔回来的
...the one who fought him, who saw Cedric Diggory get killed.
是我跟他打站 亲眼看到迪哥里被他杀死
-Harry. -Thought we heard your dulcet tones.
-哈利 -你讲话还是这广温和
-Don't bottle it up, though, mate. Let it out. -If you're all done shouting....
-别奈抑，兄弟，发泪出来 -发小完了…，
Do you wanna hear something a little more interesting?
想匠些有趣的事情吗?
if anyone has a right to know, it's Harry. if it wasn't for Harry...
哈利最有权利知道事实
...we wouldn't even know Voldemort was back.
没有他 没人会知道伏地魔回来了
He's not a child, Molly.
他不是孩子了，菜莉
But he’s not an adult either.
可是他也还不算是大人
-He's not James, Sirius. -Well, he's not your son.
-他不是磨姆，天狼星 -他不是你儿子
He's as good as.
我把他当成儿子
-Who else has he got? -Hey, Ginny.
-他没有亲人了 -和好，金妮
-He's got me. -How touchingly paternal, Black.
-他还有我 -好感人的父壳，布莱克
Perhaps Potter will grow up to be a felon, just like his godfather.
也许波特长大也会沁成罪犯 就跟他的教父一样
Now, you stay out of this, Snivellus.
你不要插话，石内下
-Snape's part of the Order? -Git.
-石内让也是风凰会成员? -讨厥抑
--about your supposed reformation.
有关你那所谓的改革
-1 know better. -So why don't you tell him?
-我知道怎样对他最好 -那你干嘛不跟他说?
-Get off it. -Quick.
-不能吃 -快
-Get it up. -Crookshanks.
-拉上来 -重腿!
-Stop it. -Get off, you bloody cat.
-不可以 -走开，臭猫
-Crookshanks. Leave it alone. -Get it up.
-牌腿，别乱来 -拉上来
-Hermione, I hate your cat. -Bad Crookshanks.
-妙牙，我讨屡人的猫 -款猫猫
Well, we'll be eating down in the kitchen.
我们要在府房吃饭
Just because you're allowed to use magic now...
你们现在可以使用魔术
...does not mean you have to whip your wands out for everything.
不代表你们可以 拿著魔杖胡并 !
Hi, Mum.
，媚
You hungry, Harry?
饿了吗，哈利?
You sure you're all right, Harry? Gave us quite a turn.
你真的没事? 我们都很握心
Harry Potter.
哈利波特
Sirius.
天狼星
This is very, very peculiar.
这真是太奇怪了
It seems your hearing in the Ministry is to be before the entire Wizengamot.
你在魔法部的匠证会 巫审加码所有的成员都会出席
I don’t understand. What has the Ministry of Magic got against me?
我搞不懂 魔法部对我有什么不满
Show him. He'll find out soon enough.
给他看吧 反正他还早会知道
He’s been attacking Dumbledore as well.
他也在择击如不利多
Fudge is using all his power, including his influence at the Daily Prophet...
夫子用邵他所有的力量 包括在《预言家日报》的影响力
...to smear anyone who claims the Dark Lord has returned.
抹黑宣称见到黑魔王回来的人
Why?
为什么 ?
He thinks Dumbledore’s after his job.
部长认为如不利多 岗钢他的工作
No one in their right mind could believe that--
太诸张了，站子才会相信…
Exactly the point. Fudge isn't in his right mind.
夫子已经神智不清
It's been twisted and warped by fear.
他的脑袋被和恐慢给择曲了
Now, fear makes people do terrible things, Harry.
恐慢会让人做出可怕的事情
The last time Voldemort gained power...
上次伏地魔春得权力
...he almost destroyed everything we hold most dear.
狼乎摧毁了我们珍惜的一切
Now he’s returned, and I'm afraid the minister will do almost anything...
他又回来了 部长会不摆手段
...to avoid facing that terrifying truth.
过避面对这个恐怖真相
We think Voldemort wants to build up his army again.
我们认为伏地魔 想要重整一支军队
Fourteen years ago, he had huge numbers at his command.
十四年前他有大批的夏牙
And not just witches and wizards, but all manner of dark creatures.
其中不只是巫师 还包括各式各样的黑暗生物
He’s been recruiting heavily, and we've been attempting to do the same.
他正在大举募兵 我们也一样
But gathering followers isn't the only thing he’s interested in.
但他想要的 莫不只是爪牙
We believe...
我们相信
... Voldemort may be after something.
伏地魔想找一样东西
Sirius.
天狼星
Something he didn’t have last time.
上次他没找到的东西
You mean like a weapon?
你是说武器吗?
No. That's enough. He's just a boy.
钓了，他只是个孩子
You say more and you might as well induct him into the Order.
再说下去 乾脆让他加入风凰会
Good. I want to join. If Voldemort’s raising an army, then I want to fight.
好啊，我想加入 伏地魔在重整军队，我要参吉
Harry.
哈利
You are hereby expelled.
因此决定开除你的学籍
Before the entire Wizengamot.
巫审加码所有的成员都会出席
Trains. Underground.
在地下开火车
Ingenious, these Muggles.
这些腰不真是隐明
Here we are.
我们到了
I’ve never used the visitors’ entrance before. Should be fun.
我从来没用过访客入口 应该会很好玩
Right. Good. I'll just get my Muggle money.
好吧，我就用我的麻爪氏吧
Terrible. Lost a lot of Galleons trading on the potions market.
我昨天超倒实 在魔药市场交易损失惨重
Daily Prophet, ladies and gentlemen. Anybody for Daily Prophet?
《预言家日报》，座要喘?
-Morning, Arthur. -Morning, Bob.
-早安，亚瑟 -早啊，巴布
Interdepartmental memos.
跨部门备忘录
We used to use owls. Mess was unbelievable.
以前都用猎头魔送折，死了
Merlin’s beard. Thank you, Kingsley.
我的天啊 谢谢你，金利
-They’ve changed the time of your hearing. -When is it?
-他们更改了匠证会时间 -改到什么时候?
In five minutes.
五分久和后
Department of Mysteries.
神秘部门到了
And I’m confident, minister, that you will do the right thing.
部长，我相信 你会做出正确决定
Yes, but we must be--
没错，不过我们必须…
Remember, during the hearing, speak only when you're spoken to.
记住，册证会上 输到你再说话
Keep calm. You've done nothing wrong.
保持冷静，你没做错事
As the Muggles say, truth will out.
就像脐瓜说的 真相会大白
Yes?
对吧?
I'm not allowed in, I’m afraid.
他们不准我陪你进去
Good luck, Harry.
祝你好还，哈利
Disciplinary hearing of the 12th of August...
这是和八月十二日的纪律黄证会
..into offenses committed by Harry James Potter...
犯案人哈利磨姆波特居住在…
..resident at Number 4 Privet Drive, Little Whinging, Surrey.
蕊里郡小惠因区水星栅街四号
Interrogators: Cornelius Oswald Fudge, Minister of Mag--
债讯人魔法部长 康尼留斯夫子…
Witness for the defense.
我是辩方证人 !
Albus Percival Wulfric...
阿不思博知维巫服利…
...-Brian Dumbledore.
布莱思恤不利多
You got our message that the time and place of the hearing...
你应该收到 区证会时间地点…
-...had been changed, did you? - must have missed it.
-更改的信息，对吧? -我一定是错过了
But by a happy mistake, l arrived at the Ministry three hours early.
不过幸好我提前三小时 来魔法部
The charges?
界名是什么?
The charges against the accused are as follows:
以下是被告的罪名
.and in full awareness of the illegality of his actions...
总且知道 此为媚法行为的情况下
...Pproduce a Patronus Charm...
在一个麻不面前
...in the presence of a Muggle.”
施展访法咒^
-Do you deny producing said Patronus? -No, but--
-你是否承认以上的指控?9 -是的 ， 但是…
And you were aware that you were forbidden to use magic outside school...
你也知道未满十七弓 在校外…
-...while under the age of 17? -Yes, I was, but--
-不准使用魔法吗? -我知道，可是…
Witches and wizards of the Wizengamot--
各位巫审加码的巫师和女巫
I was only doing it because of the Dementors.
催狂魔出现我才会这广做
Dementors?
催狂魔?
In Little Whinging?
跑去小惠因区 ?
That's quite clever.
这是很隐明的藉口
Muggles can't see Dementors, can they, boy?
太爪看不到催狂魔，对吧?
-Highly convenient. -I'm not lying.
-这藉口真好用 -我没说议
-There were two of them, and if I hadn’t-- -Enough.
-有十个，要是我没… -金了!
I'm sorry to interrupt what I’m sure would have been a very well-rehearsed story...
抱雏我要打世 这个篇好的故事…
...but since you can produce no witnesses of the event--
但是由於这起事件 没有目击证人
Pardon me, minister, but as it happens, we can.
部长，其实现场有目击证人
Please describe the attack.
请描述一下攻击事件
What did they look like?
他们长什么样子?
Well, one of them was very large and the other rather skinny.
其中一个很胖，另一个很瘦
Not the boys. The Dementors.
我不是说男孩子们 是催狂魔
Oh, right, right. Well, big.
是哦，他们很高大
Cloaked. Then everything went cold...
身穿斗禾 然后…四周变得很冷
..as though all the happiness had gone from the world.
好像所有的快乐都从世上消失
Now, look here. Dementors don’t just wander into a Muggle suburb...
大家区我说 催狂魔不会随便跑到及瓜社区
..-and happen across a wizard. The odds are astronomical.
碰巧遇到一个巫师 不可能有这征巧合
I don't think anyone would believe...
我想，没有人认为…
...the Dementors were there by coincidence, minister.
催狂魔去那里 只是个巧合， 部长
I'm sure I must have misunderstood you, professor.
我一定是误解你了，教授
Dementors are, after all, under the control of the Ministry of Magic.
翌竟催狂魔受到魔法部的控管
And it’s so silly of me, but it sounded for a moment as though...
这庆说很傻 不过你好像暗示…
... you were suggesting that the Ministry had ordered the attack on this boy.
攻击事件是魔法部下的命令
That would be disturbing indeed, Madam Undersecretary...
这的确令人不安 政务次长女士
...which is why I’m sure the Ministry will be mounting a full-scale inquiry...
所以魔法部一定会进行全面调查
...into why the two Dementors were so very far from Azkaban...
雨个催狂魔为何踪郊阿兹卡班
...-and why they mounted an attack without authorization.
以及他们为何未经授权发支攻击
Of course, there is someone...
当然一定是有人…
...who might be behind the attack.
策动这次攻击
Cornelius, l implore you to see reason.
康尼留斯，请你看清真相
The evidence that the Dark Lord has returned is incontrovertible.
黑魔王回来的证据 已经非常明显
He is not back.
他根本没回来 !
In the matter of Harry Potter...
至恭哈利波特的界名
...the law clearly states...
法律明文规定
...that magic may be used before Muggles in life-threatening situations.
生命受威草时 可在太扑面前用魔法
Laws can be changed if necessary, Dumbledore.
法律可依实际状况而修改
Clearly. Has it become practice to hold a full criminal trial...
为何单纯的未成年使用魔法事件
...to deal with a simple matter of underage magic?
要搞到人这样大费周章全面审判?
Those in favor of conviction?
认为他有罪的人请举手
Those in favor of clearing the accused of all charges?
认为该撤销所有控诉的人请举手
Cleared of all charges.
撤销所有控诉
Professor.
教授 !
Padfoot. Are you barking mad?
软足，你是不是疯了?
You'll blow the entire operation.
你会害我们的行动曝光
Sirius, what are you doing here? If somebody sees you....
天狼星，你来干嘛?
I had to see you off, didn’t I?
我一定要向你道别
What's life without a little risk?
人生本来就友满了风险
I don’t wanna see you get chucked back in Azkaban.
我不想看到 你被关进阿兹卡班
Don't worry about me.
不要担心我
Anyway, I wanted you to have this.
拿去，我要把这张照月给你
Original Order of the Phoenix.
风凰会的创立成员
She was killed two weeks after this was taken.
拍完这攻照月 两遇和后她就遇害
Voldemort wiped out her entire family.
伏地魔负死了她全家人
Frank and Alice Longbottom.
法苦克跟艾时斯隆巴顿
Neville’s parents.
奈威的爸妈
They suffered a fate worse than death, you ask me.
他们的遭遇比死亡更惨
It's been 14 years.
都已经十四年了
And still a day doesn't go by I don't miss your dad.
但是我没有一天 不想念你爸爸
Do you really think there’s going to be a war, Sirius?
你觉得有可能会开战吗?
It feels like it did before.
感觉跟上次很像
You keep it.
你留著吧
Anyway, I suppose you're the young ones now.
我猜你们是新一代的辣士
I'll see you at the train.
火车上见
Bye-bye, darling.
再见…
l love you.
我党你
Hold my hand, lovey.
挛好我的手，厅党的
There they are. They're in the far carriage.
他们来了 他们在下一点的车麻
Bye.
再见…
I'm surprised the Ministry's still letting you walk around free.
我很意外魔法部会放你出来
Better enjoy it while you can.
还有自由的时候 好好享受一下
l expect there’s a cell in Azkaban with your name on it.
你还早会被关进阿兹卡班
-What'd I tell you? Complete nutter. -Just stay away from me!
-我早说了， 你是个站子 -郊我下一点 !
It’s only Malfoy.
马份就是这样
What'd you expect?
狗改不了吃尿
Hi, guys.
你们好
-Hey, Neville. -Hey there, Neville.
-嘴，泰威
What is it?
这是什么 ?
-What's what? -That. Pulling the carriage.
-什么东西? -那个拉马车的东西
Nothing’s pulling the carriage, Harry.
没有永西在拉马车啊
It’s pulling itself, like always.
轧车一直都是自己动的
You're not going mad.
你没有发疯
I can see them too.
我也能看到怨们
You're just as sane as I am.
你跟我一样没发站
Everyone, this is Loony Love--
各位，这是露站子…
What an interesting necklace.
好有意思的项刍哦
It's a charm, actually.
这是史话项妇
Keeps away the Nargles.
可以赶走水灯器
Hungry.
我好饿
I hope there's pudding.
希望有布丁吃
-What’s a Nargle? -No idea.
-水粳由是什么? -不晓得
Good evening, children.
了晚安，和孩子们
Now, we have two changes in staffing this year.
今年的教职员有两项变动
We're pleased to welcome back Professor Grubbly-Plank...
让我们获迎萝柏戎教授回来
...who’'ll be taking Care of Magical Creatures...
她将在海格教授离开的期间
... while Professor Hagrid is on temporary leave.
暂时代理奇葡蚀育学
We also wish to welcome our new Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher...
也请获迎新的 黑魔法防潮街老师
...Professor Dolores Umbridge.
桃纪缘恩不里居教授
And I'm sure you'll all join me in wishing the professor good luck.
大家都跟我一样 祝教授一切顺利
Now, as usual, our caretaker, Mr. Filch, has asked me to remind you--
管理员郝七先生 照常要我提醒各位…
She was at my hearing. She works for Fudge.
她有出席册证会 她蔡夫子工作
Thank you, headmaster, for those kind words of welcome.
校长，谢谢你热烈地欢迎我
And how lovely to see all your bright...
我很高浴看到这广多亮路…
.. happy faces smiling up at me.
快乐的脸蛋 带著微笑看我
I'm sure we're all going to be very good friends.
我相信我们一定会成为好朋友
-That’s likely.
-是喔
The Ministry of Magic has always considered...
魔法部最重视的
...the education of young witches and wizards to be of vital importance.
一向都是年轻巫师和女巫的教育
Although each headmaster...
引然每任校长都会蔚这所…
...has brought something new to this historic school...
历史悠久的学校带来新的创意
...progress for the sake of progress must be discouraged.
但是绝对不能只为了发展而发展
Let us preserve what must be preserved...
让我们保存必须保存的一切
...perfect what can be perfected...
达到能金思到的完美境界
..-and prune practices that ought to be prohibited.
冰且禁止应该禁止的续加课程
Thank you, Professor Umbridge. That really was most illuminating.
谢谢你，思不里居教授 这番话真是令人茸塞顿开
-Illuminating? What a load of waffle. -What’s it mean?
-和拜斌，全是一堆广话 -到底是什么意思?
Magic is forbidden in the corridors....
在走廊上不准施展魔法…
It means the Ministry's interfering at Hogwarts.
意思是魔法部 开始干涉霍格苇益了
Dean, Seamus.
丁，西其
-Good holiday? -All right.
-暑假好玩吧?9 -还好
Better than Seamus’, anyway.
至少比西莫好多了
Me mum didn’t want me to come back this year.
我杂今年不想要我回来
-Why not? -Let me see. Because of you.
-为什么 ? -该怎夭说? 都是因为你
The Daily Prophet's been saying a lot of things about you and Dumbledore.
《预言家日报》说了很多关於你 还有地不利多的事
What, your mum believes them?
你杂居然相信 ?
Nobody was there the night Cedric died.
西追死的那晚没有别人在
I guess you should read the Prophet, then, like your stupid mother.
那就跟你的春姻妈一样看报纸 你想要知道的事上面都有
-Don't talk about my mother. -l'll have a go at anyone that calls me a liar.
-不准你这样说我妈 ! -谁说我是骗子，我就跟谁单挑
-What’'s going on? -He’s mad, is what's going on.
-有问题吗? -他就是最大的问题
Do you believe the rubbish he’s come out with about You-Know-Who?
你相信他说的 那个人的议话吗?
Yeah. I do.
对，我相信
Has anyone else got a problem with Harry?
还有谁对哈利有总见 ?
-You all right? -Fine.
-你没事吧? -没事
Seamus was bang out of order, mate.
西莫真的是太过分了
-But he'll come through, you'll see. -l said, I'm fine, Ron.
-不过他会想通的，等著鸭 -我说我没事，荣轧 !
Right. I'll just leave you to your thoughts, then.
好吧，那我就让你静一静吧
Harry.
哈利
Bring it over here. Over here.
让它赤过来
Oh, go on, Seamus. Go on, get it.
西英，把它打下来
Good morning, children.
早安，孩子们
Ordinary Wizarding Level examinations.
普通巫术等级检测
O-W-Ls.
OO 一双一工一S
More commonly known as OWLs.
通常都简称为普等巫测
Study hard and you will be rewarded.
用功叭书就一定会有回报
Fail to do so, and the consequences may be severe.
否则下场可能会是一塌糊涂
Your previous instruction in this subject has been disturbingly uneven.
你们之前的教材品质参差不守
But you'll be pleased to know, from now on...
(《黑魔法防案街》)
...you will be following a carefully structured, Ministry-approved...
将学加反有好话结构
...course of defensive magic. Yes?
经过魔法部核准的防舍街课程 什么事?
There’s nothing in here about using defensive spells?
课本没教如何使用防案允语
Using spells?
使用响语?
Well, can’t imagine why you would need to use spells in my classroom.
我的课堂上不需要使用咒语
We're not gonna use magic?
我们不会使用咒语 ?
You'll be learning about defensive spells in a secure, risk-free way.
你们会用安全的方法 学习防舍魔法
What use is that? If we're attacked, it won't be risk-free.
那有什么用呢? 遇到攻击一定会有危险
Students will raise their hands when they speak in my class.
想要发言的同学请先举手
It is the view of the Ministry...
魔法部认为…
...that a theoretical knowledge will be sufficient...
学习基础理论…
...to get you through your examinations...
就能通过普等巫测
.. Which, after all, is what school is all about.
愉竟这才是教学的目的
And how's theory supposed to prepare us for what's out there?
不能应付外面的危险
There is nothing out there, dear.
外面世没有危险啊
Who do you imagine wants to attack children like yourself?
谁会攻击像你这样的小孩?
Oh, I don’t know. Maybe Lord Voldemort.
不晓得，也许是伏地魔王
Now, let me make this quite plain.
有一件事情我要说清楚
You have been told...
有人告诉你们
...that a certain dark wizard is at large once again.
有一个黑巫师又再度出现了
-This is a lie. -It’s not a lie. saw him. I fought him.
-这是个谎言 -我没说议，我看通他、对抗过他
Detention, Mr. Potter.
劳动服务，波特先生 !
Cedric Diggory dropped dead of his own accord?
你是说迪哥里
Cedric Diggory’s death was a tragic accident.
西仍迪哥里的死 是一场意外悲盎
It was murder. Voldemort killed him.
伏地魔负死他，刀知道
Enough!
钓了!
Enough.
不要说了
See me later, Mr. Potter. My office.
待会儿到我办公室来 波特先生
Come in.
进来
Good evening, Mr. Potter.
晚安，波特
Sit.
坐吧
You're going to be doing some lines for me today, Mr. Potter.
我要你帮我窟一些句子，波特
No, not with your quill.
不准用你的羽毛笔
Going to be using a rather special one of mine.
你要用我的特卸羽毛笔
Now...
现在
...[ want you to write, “I must not tell lies.”
开始高 “我不可以说议“
How many times?
要高贱次?
Well, let’s say for as long as it takes for the message to sink in.
一直窟到这名话 烙印在你心里
You haven't given me any ink.
你没有给我墨水
Oh, you won't need any ink.
你不需要墨水
Yes?
怎庆了?
-Nothing. -That’s right.
-没什么 -这才关
Because you know, deep down...
因为你在内心深咕也知道…
..-you deserve to be punished.
这个惩罚是公平的
Don’t you, Mr. Potter?
对不对，波特?
Go on.
继续吧
Get out of class whenever you like.
-会让你生病的糖果 -人这样才能随时请假
Obtain hours of pleasure from unprofitable boredom.
下疮无聊的教室出去玩
Care for another?
要不要再来一块?
-I'm not asking you to write all of it for me. -Please.
-我又不是要炼攻我窟全部 -拜旗
I've been busy studying for these stupid OWL exams.
我正忙著准备讨屡的普等巫测
Pll do the introduction. That's all.
我只能帮你窟序言
Hermione, you're honestly the most wonderful person I've ever met.
妙棱，人是我认识最好的人
-And if I’m ever rude to you again.... -l'll know you've gone back to normal.
-我再也不会对你没礼貌 -才怪，你一定会
What’s wrong with your hand?
你的手怎厅了?
Nothing.
没什让
The other hand.
另一集手
-You've got to tell Dumbledore. -No.
-你一定要告诉雾不利多 --不
Dumbledore’s got enough on his mind right now.
他已经有很多事情要烦懂
I don’t want to give Umbridge the satisfaction.
我不会让恩不里居得盈的
Bloody hell, Harry. The woman’s torturing you.
拜旗，她这是对你体罚
-lIf the parents knew about this.... -l haven't got any of those, have I, Ron?
-如果让父母知道… -问题是我没有父母，对吧?
Harry, you've got to report this.
哈利，你一定要向校长报告
-It’s perfectly simple. You're being-- -No, it’s not.
-事情很单纯，只要… -不，状不单纯
Hermione, whatever this is, it’s not simple.
妙对，这件事一点也不单纯
You don’t understand.
你不会懂的
Then help us to.
解释给我们区咱
Dear Padfoot...
“亲爱的软足
...f hope you're all right.
希望你一切安好
it's starting to get colder here. Winter is definitely on the way.
这里念来盒冷 冬天肯定快到了
In spite of being back at Hogwarts, ! feel more alone than ever.
我牙然回到学校 估赏得更孤音
i know you, of all people, will understand.
你一定比别人更能葛螃解“
Hello, Harry Potter.
你好，哈利波特
-Your feet. Aren't they cold? -Bit.
-炼光著有聊，不会冷吗?9 -有一点
Unfortunately, all my shoes have mysteriously disappeared.
我的鞋子好像都神秘消失了
I suspect Nargles are behind it.
我怀疑是水粳占干的好事
-What are they? -They’re called Thestrals.
-和拖们是什么 ? -骑士医鬼马
They're quite gentle, really, but people avoid them because they're a bit....
季们很温囊，不通… 人们过避物们，国为籽们有点…
Different.
不一样
But why can't the others see them?
为什么其他人都看不到?
They can only be seen by people who've seen death.
只有面对过死亡的人才看得到
So you've known someone who's died, then?
有炼认识的人死了?
My mum.
我怒
She was quite an extraordinary witch, but she did like to experiment...
她是个了不起的女巫 但是她很喜欢做实验
..-and one day, one of her spells went badly wrong.
有一天她的咒语 出了居重意外
-l was 9. -I'm sorry.
-当时我九战 -很遗居
Yes, it was rather horrible.
真的很不好受
I do feel very sad about it sometimes, but I’ve got Dad.
我有时候膛会觉得难过
We both believe you, by the way.
对了“，我跟我爸都相信你
That He-Who-Must-Not-Be-Named is back, and you fought him...
那个我们不能说出名字的人回来了 你也对抗明他
...and the Ministry and the Prophet are conspiring against you.
魔法部和报社 队谋对付你和校长
Thanks. It seems you're about the only ones that do.
谢谢，你们好像是 唯一相信我的人
I don’t think that’s true.
我党得茧不是这样
But I suppose that's how he wants you to feel.
不过我猜他要让你这刻想
What do you mean?
什么意思?
Well, if 1 were You-Know-Who...
如果我是那个人
...['d want you to feel cut off from everyone else...
我就会让你党得被大家孤立
...because if it’s just you alone...
只要你势音力孤…
..-you’re not as much of a threat.
就构不成威锅
-Do you ever stop eating? -What? I’m hungry.
-你就不能不吃东西吗? -人家肚子饿嘛
Harry.
哈利
Can I join you?
我可以坐这里吗?
Pardon me, professor, but what exactly are you insinuating?
教授，炼对我有什么意见?
lam merely requesting that when it comes to my students...
当虹在处罚我的学生
..-you conform to the prescribed disciplinary practices.
请你一定要遵守 学校现有的规定
So silly of me, but it sounds...
我没有贡错吧
..as if you're questioning my authority in my own classroom...
你好像在质疑
...Minerva.
米奈娃
Not at all, Dolores, merely your medieval methods.
我没这个意思，桃乐缘
lam sorry, dear.
我觉得很遗性
But to question my practices is to question the Ministry...
但是质疑我 就是搞疑魔法部
..and by extension, the minister himself.
也就是质疑部长本人
lam a tolerant woman...
我的包容力很强
...but the one thing I will not stand for is disloyalty.
但是我缀不容忍对部长不忠心
Disloyalty.
不上串心
Things at Hogwarts are far worse than I feared.
韦格革兹的情况 比我想像的更爆
Cornelius will want to take immediate action.
部长一定会电上探取紧急措施
What's happened to Dumbledore?
好不利多怎庆样了?
Having already revolutionized...
思不里居改革了…
...the teaching of Defense Against the Dark Arts...
黑魔法防舍教学
.--Dolores Umbridge will, as high inquisitor, have powers...
她身为霍格华兹总督察 扩有绝对的权力
...to address the seriously falling standards at Hogwarts School.
提高韦格鞋兹学校 下滑的水洗
Just one question, dear.
我只有一个问题
You've been in this post how long, exactly?
你担任这份教职有多久了?
You applied first for the Defense Against the Dark Arts post, is that correct?
你起初是申请 黑魔法防售教授，对不对?
Yes.
是的
But you were unsuccessful?
但是你六没有成功
Obviously.
很显然
Could you please predict something for me?
请你为我预测将来好吗 ?
I'm sorry?
你说什么 ?
Move those mouths.
嘴巴张大一点
One teensy little prophecy?
来个小小的预言吧
Pity.
真可惜
No, wait. Wait, no. I think I do see something.
不，等一等 我好像看到什么了
Yes, 1 do. Something dark.
一件黑暗的事情
You are in grave danger.
你身陷极大的危险
Lovely.
太好了
Cho. What's going on?
张秋，和发生什么事?
It's Professor Trelawney.
崔老妮教授出事了
Sixteen years I've lived and taught here.
十六年来我住在这里教书
Hogwarts is my home.
韦格革兹是我的家
You can't do this.
你不能把我超走
Actually, I can.
老实说，我能
Something you'd like to say?
你有话要说唉?
Oh, there are several things I would like to say.
我是有很多话想说出来
There....
别伤心…
Professor McGonagall, might I ask you to escort Sybil back inside?
厅烦人送崔教授回到学校
Sybil, dear. This way.
西碧，来吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Dumbledore, may I remind you that under the terms...
如不利多 容我提醒你…
...of Educational Decree Number 23, as enacted by the minister--
根据部长颁布的 教育章程第二十三条…
You have the right to dismiss my teachers.
你有权力开除学校老师
You do not, however, have the authority to banish them from the grounds.
但是人扰权 把老师从学校超走
That power remains with the headmaster.
只有校长有这个权力
For now.
没多久了
Don't you all have studying to do?
你们都没有功课要做吗?
Professor.
教授 !
Professor Dumbledore. Professor!
如不利多教授 ! 教授!
Professor Dumbledore.
好不利多教授 !
That foul, evil, old gargoyle.
一元收吓的老巫婆
We're not learning how to defend ourselves. We're not learning how to pass our OWLs.
我们根本没有学到防舍入 也没有在准备普等巫测
She's taking over the entire school.
她掌控了整个学校
Security has been and will remain the Ministry's top priority.
魔法部一向以 人民安全为第一优先
Furthermore, we have convincing evidence...
另外，我们有证所显示
...that these disappearances are the work...
这些失路事件
...0f notorious mass murderer Sirius Black.
是恶名昭彰的天狼星所为
Harry.
哈利
Sirius.
天狼星
-What are you doing here? -Answering your letter.
-你来这里做什么? -回你的信啊
You said you were worried about Umbridge. What's she doing?
你说你很担心恩不里居 她在干嘛?
Training you to kill half-breeds?
训练你们角订御?
-She’s not letting us use magic at all. -Well, I’m not surprised.
-她不准我们使用魔法 -我一点也不意外
The latest intelligence is that Fudge doesn’t want you trained in combat.
聘说夫子不要你们 做任何战门训综
Combat?
战同?
What does he think, we're forming some sort of wizard army?
他怕我们组成魔法师军围吗?
That's exactly what he thinks.
这就是他的想法
That Dumbledore is assembling his own forces to take on the Ministry.
他怕痢不利多 招募军队接管魔法部
He’s becoming more paranoid by the minute.
他全来鳄神经分分
The others wouldn’t want me telling you this, Harry...
其他人不希望 我跟你说这些事
...but things aren't going at all well with the Order.
风凰会的行动花不是很顺利
Fudge is blocking the truth at every turn...
夫子用邵手段防堵真相
...and these disappearances are just how it started before.
这些失路事件 跟上次完全一样
Voldemort is on the move.
伏地魔开始行动了
Well, what can we do?
我们该怎庆做?
Someone's coming.
有人来了
I'm sorry I can't be of more help.
抱攻我帮不上太多忙
But for now, at least, it looks like you're on your own.
看来，现在… 你们必须壮自己了
He really is out there, isn’t he?
他真的开始行动了
We've got to be able to defend ourselves.
我们一定要能金保访自己
And if Umbridge refuses to teach us how, we need someone who will.
因不里居不肯教 那我们就找别人
Harry.
哈利
This is mad. Who'd wanna be taught by me?
这太疯狂了，谁要让我教?
I'm a nutter, remember?
大家都说我是站子
Look on the bright side: you can’t be any worse than old toad face.
乐观一点 你不会比那老蛤蜡莉
-Thanks, Ron. -I'm here for you, mate.
-谢了，荣因 -我一定会捍你
Who's supposed to be meeting us, then?
有谁会来?
Just a couple of people.
只有狗个人
Lovely spot.
这地方真不错
Thought it would be safer off the beaten track.
我党得和偏下的地方比较安全
Matey, come back here.
羊仔，给我回来
Hi.
大家好
So you all know why we're here.
大家都知道来这儿的目的
We need a teacher.
我们需要老师
A proper teacher.
真正的老师
One who's had experience defending themselves against the Dark Arts.
用防祭入对付过 黑魔王的老师
-Why?
-为什么 ?
Because You-Know-Who's back, you tosspot.
那个人回来了，策重
-So he says. -So Dumbledore says.
-那是哈利说的 -好不利多也这广说
So Dumbledore says because he says.
如不利多 是因为哈利才这广说
The point is, where's the proof?
重点是证据在哪里?
If Potter could tell us more about how Diggory got killed....
波特应该说出 迪哥里被角的经过
I'm not gonna talk about Cedric, so if that’s why you’re here, clear out now.
我不会谈这件事 如果你们因此而来，那可以走了
Come on, Hermione. They're here because they think I'm some sort of freak.
-走吧，妙林，他们全把我当怪胎 -等一下
Is it true you can produce a Patronus Charm?
你真的会施展访法咒吧?9
Yes.
没错
I’ve seen it.
我亲眼看过
Blimey, Harry. I didn’t know you could do that.
真的假的? 我不知道你会耶
And he killed a basilisk, with the sword in Dumbledore’s office.
他用性不利多办公室… 的一把剑角死蛇妖
It’s true.
是真的
Third year, he fought off about a hundred Dementors at once.
他一个人击退上百个催狂魔
Last year, he really did fight off You-Know-Who in the flesh.
去年他还跟那个人 面对面打癌过
Wait.
等等
Look, it all sounds great when you say it like that...
你们这广说 英超来好像很了不起
...but the truth is, most of that was just luck.
老实说，我只是很幸运
I didn’t know what I was doing half the time. I nearly always had help.
我多半根本就不知所措 公平每次都有人帮助
-He’s just being modest. -No, Hermione, I’m not.
-他只是谦庶 -我没有，妙忆
Facing this stuff in real life is not like school.
面对真正的散人和上课不同
In school, if you make a mistake, you can just try again tomorrow.
上课犯了错，能再试一次
But out there...
可是在现实世界
...when you're a second away from being murdered...
当你就快要被杀死
...or watching a friend die tight before your eyes....
或是亲眼看著 朋友在你面前死去
You don’t know what that’s like.
你们不会上解那征感受
You're right, Harry, we don't.
你说的对，哈利 我们是不螃解
That’s why we need your help.
我们不上解才需要你的帮助
Because if we're going to have any chance at beating...
如果我们必须对抗…
...Voldemort....
伏地魔的话
He’s really back.
他真的回来了
Right. First we need to find a place to practice...
我们要找一个
... where Umbridge won't find out.
思不里居查不到的地方张辕
-The Shrieking Shack. -It’s too small.
-央叫屋 -那里太小了
-Forbidden Forest? -Not bloody likely.
-禁辟的森林呢? -那里太丽怖了
Harry, what happens if Umbridge does find out?
哈利，被恩不里居发现会怎样 ?
Who cares?
谁在乎啊?
I mean, it’s sort of exciting, isn’t it, breaking the rules?
我是说… 违反校规很刺激耶
Who are you and what have you done with Hermione?
你是谁? 你把妙姥怎和了?
Anyway, at least we know one positive thing that came from today.
起码今天有了一项正面收获
What's that?
是什么?
Cho couldn't take her eyes off you, could she?
纪秋和从头到尾都盯著你看
Right. Over the next few days, we should each come up...
接下来这凤天 我们要找儿个…
..-with a couple of possibilities of places we can practice.
可以张加的地方
We've got to make sure, wherever it is, there’s no chance she can find us.
而且要确定不能被她找到
Will do, Harry.
没问题，哈利
All student organizations are henceforth disbanded.
所有学生组织即刻解散
Any student in noncompliance will be expelled.
学生若有不从随即开除
Watch where you're going, Longbottom.
走路要看路，隆巴顿
You've done it, Neville. You found the Room of Requirement.
你成功了，奈威 你找到万订室了
The what?
什么?
It’s also known as the Come and Go Room.
这又叫做来去室
The Room of Requirement only appears when a person has real need of it.
菌应室只在最需要时 才会出现
And it's always equipped for the seeker’s needs.
里面的配备完全符合你的需要
So say you really needed the toilet....
需要上高所也会出现?
Charming, Ronald. But, yes, that is the general idea.
你很白痪耶 不过就跟你说的差不多
It’s brilliant. It’s like Hogwarts wants us to fight back.
太棒了，好像堆格革兹 希望我们起来抗事
Expelliarmus.
去去，武器走!
I'm hopeless.
我没护了
You're just flourishing your wand too much. Try it like this. Expelliarmus.
你只是把魔杖甩得太用力 这样斌试看，去去，臣器走!
You will please copy the approved text four times...
大家请把魔法部 核准的教科书抄写四饥
...to ensure maximum retention.
才能确定通通记熟
-There will be no need to talk. -No need to think’s more like it.
-考试时不准交谈 -我看是不准用脑袋吧
-Expelliarmus. -Wands away.
-去去，武器走 -魔杖收起来
Stunning is one of the most useful spells in your arsenal.
香击如是最有用的响语之一
It's a wizard’s bread and butter, really.
它是巫师的基本配备
So come on, then, Nigel. Give it your best shot.
来吧，奈吉，你来试试看
Stupefy!
吊唱失!
Good. Not bad at all, Nigel. Well done.
很好，还不错 泰吉，做得好
Don’t worry. I'll go easy on you.
别担心，我会轻一点
Thanks, Ronald.
谢了，和楷思
-Come on, Ron.
-加油，药恩…
-You can do it.
-你一定闪得到 -加油，荣思
-One Sickle. -You're on.
-我赌一西可 -赌了
Stupefy.
吊唱失!
-Thank you. -Shut up.
-谢了 -闭嘴
Il let her do that. It's good manners, isn’t it?
这是基本礼貌嘛
It was completely intentional.
我是真的故意让她的
Up you come. Would you like a cup of tea?
上来吧，想喝杯茶吧?
Now, focus on a fixed point and try again.
专心对准固定的点 再试一次
Expelliarmus.
去去，武器走!
Very good. Keep your concentration.
很好，注意力保持集中
Great.
非常好
A little higher.
再拿高一点
I'm okay. I’m okay.
没事，我没事
-Stupefy.
-虽吊失!
Those wishing to join the Inquisitorial Squad for extra credit...
学生欲加入督察小组 以求加分者
. .-May sign up in the high inquisitor's office.
请向总督察室登记
Diminuendo.
咪咪缩
Working hard is important, but there’s something that matters even more:
努力很重要 但有一件事更重要
Believing in yourself.
那就是相信自己
-Expelliarmus. -Levicorpus. Got it.
-去去，武器走! -个个吊 了成了
Think of it this way.
想想看
Every great wizard in history has started out...
史上每个伟大的巫师
..as nothing more than what we are now: students.
跟我们一样 一开始也是学生
If they can do it, why not us?
他们做得到，我们也行
-Stupefy. -Expelliarmus.
-虽吊失! -去去，武器走!
Expelliarmus.
去去，武器走…
Reducto.
嗓嗓消
-Expelliarmus.
-去去，武器走!
Expelliarmus.
去去，武器走!
Fantastic, Neville. Well done, man.
太好了“，奈威 做得好
So that’s it for this lesson.
这堂课就到此为目
Now, we're not gonna be meeting again until after the holidays.
下一堂课是在圣诞节以后
So just keep practicing on your own as best you can.
回家以和后 刷量自己偷偷张因
And well done, everyone. Great, great work.
大家都表现得很好 真的很棒
Well done, mate.
做得好
Thanks.
谢谢
See you after Christmas.
于诞节和后再见
See you in the Common Room, Harry.
我们到交谊麻等你，哈利
-Thanks a lot, Harry. -No worries.
-真的很谢谢你 -不客气
-Thank you so much. -Not at all. Merry Christmas.
-谢谢你 -村诞季快乐，不客气
-Thank you, Harry. -Thank you. Merry Christmas.
-谢谢，盏诞季快乐 -哈利，吾诞季快乐
-Merry Christmas. -Have a good Christmas.
-本诞季快乐 -本诞季快乐，哈利
-Have a great Christmas, Luna. -We've been thinking.
-你也一样，露娜 -哈利，我们一直在想
We could always slip Umbridge some Puking Pastilles.
可以在她的茶 放吐吐糖或发烧糖
Or Fever Fudge. They give you massive, pus-filled boils--
保证她脸上长满一堆有的漫的
Sounds great, guys. Would you excuse me?
英超来很棒，借过一下
Are you all right? ! heard Umbridge gave you a rough time the other day.
你没事吧? 聘说前仍天恩不里居为鸡你
Yeah. I’m okay.
对，我没事
Anyway, it’s worth it.
我党得很值得
It’s just, learning all this...
只是…学避这些咒话
...makes me wonder whether, if he'd known it....
让我一直狂 他到底会不会
Cedric did know this stuff.
西追吗?9 西追很懂这些刀语
He was really good.
他是高手
It’s just, Voldemort was better.
只是伏地魔比他属害
You're a really good teacher, Harry.
你是一个好老师，哈利
I’ve never been able to stun anything before.
我以前用香击吕都没成功过
Probably full of Nargles, though.
说不定长满了水粳器
What are Nargles?
水类不是什么 ?
No idea.
我也不知道
Well, how was it?
感觉怎订样 ?
Wet.
混混的
I mean, she was sort of crying.
我是说她在如
That bad at it, are you?
你的吻功那记痣哦
I'm sure Harry’s kissing was more than satisfactory.
哈利的技术谭该在水准以上
Cho spends half her time crying these days.
最近张秋常常在器
You'd think a bit of snogging would cheer her up.
热吻也没让她开心起来
Don't you understand how she must be feeling?
你不懂她的感受吗?
Well, obviously she’s feeling sad about Cedric...
她很明显在为西追准过
..and confused about liking Harry and guilty about kissing him...
又为喜数哈利而亲他 感到内疯
...conflicted because Umbridge might sack her mum from the Ministry...
思不里居还威偶要开除她妈
..and frightened of failing her OWLs because she’s worrying about everything.
又害怕普等巫测没有过 她每天都有很多烦懂
One person couldn't feel all that. They'd explode.
一个人有这麻多烦懂 一定会瘦掉
Just because you've got the emotional range of a teaspoon....
不要因为你没大脑 就这样讲别人
Harry.
哈利
Voldemort may be after something.
伏地魔想找一样东西
Something he didn't have last time.
上次他没找到的东西
Harry.
哈利
In the dream, were you standing next to the victim...
你在枕中 是站在受害人淮冰
...or looking down at the scene?
还是劣秽著整个过程?
Neither. It was like I....
都不是，我觉得…
Will you please just tell me what's happening?
教授，我是怎庆了?
Everard, Arthur's on guard duty tonight.
埃弗拉，今晚亚瑟负责守和本
Make sure he’s found by the right people.
确认我方的人能找到他
-Sir. -Phineas.
-教授 ! -辈尼1!
You must go to your portrait at Grimmauld Place.
赶快去你在古里某街的履像
Tell them that Arthur Weasley is gravely injured...
告诉大家 亚瑟卫斯理受了重伤
..and his children will be arriving there soon by Portkey.
他的小孩会用 任意门给是超过去
They've got him, Albus. It was close, but they think he'll make it.
找到他了“，幸好他还活著
What's more, the Dark Lord failed to acquire it.
而且黑魔王没拿到东西
Oh, thank goodness. Next we need to--
谢天谢地，现在我们要…,
Look at me!
看著我!
What’s happening to me?
我到底是怎庆回事?
You wished to see me, headmaster?
你找我有事吗，校长?
Oh, Severus. I’m afraid we can’t wait. Not even till the morning.
石和内卜，我们不能再等了 划至不能等到明天早上
Otherwise, we'll all be vulnerable.
否则我们都有危险
It appears there’s a connection...
黑魔王的心智
...between the Dark Lord’s mind and your own.
跟你的心智似乎有联结
Whether he is, as yet, aware of this connection is, for the moment, unclear.
我们不清楚 他是否发现了这个联结
Pray he remains ignorant.
希望他永于不会发现
You mean, if he knows about it, then...
如果他知道…
-...he'll be able to read my mind? -Read it, control it...
-就知道我在想什么 ? -不但知道，还能控制你
...unhinge it.
把你带疯
In the past, it was often the Dark Lord's pleasure...
以前黑魔王喜欢
...to invade the minds of his victims...
侵入猎物的心智
..creating visions designed to torture them into madness.
利用幻觉 把这些人折磨到发瘦
Only after extracting the last exquisite ounce of agony...
当他让一个人痛苦到受不了
..-only when he had them literally begging for death, would he finally...
开始求黑魔王把他杀掉
..-kill them.
黑魔王才会条了他
Used properly, the power of Occlumency...
只要小心使用 人锁心咒的力量
..-Will help shield you from access or influence.
就能帮助你抵抄他的影响
In these lessons, I will attempt to penetrate your mind.
在上课时 我会试图穿租你的心智
You will attempt to resist.
你必须设法抵抗
Prepare yourself.
准备好了
Legilimens.
破破心 上
Concentrate, Potter. Focus.
专心，波特 集中注意力
Ho, ho, ho. Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Here we go.
好了
Daddy's back.
区爸回来了
Sit down, everybody, sit down. That's it. Now, presents.
大家坐下来 很好，分礼物了
-And a nice big box for Ron. -Big box for you. And....
-此思的礼物很大哦 -超大的
Fred and George. Come on, open up.
弗雷，乔治，快打开
-l want to see your faces. -Yes.
-我想看你们的表情 一 对 可可
-Try it on. -Thanks, Mum. It's perfect.
-试试看 -谢谢始，太棒了
-Just what he wanted, actually. -Yeah. Right. Thanks, Mum.
-全都是你们要的礼物 -是呵，谢谢，娟
Come on, then, everybody. Let's clear this away.
来，大家把东西清一清
Oh, Harry, Harry.
哈利，哈利
There you are.
你来了
-Happy Christmas. -Thank you.
-本诞快乐 -谢谢
-Lovely to have you with us.
-你能来真好
Now, Daddy. Pass that to Daddy.
好了“，把酒拿给爸爸
-Thank you. -Has everybody got?
-谢谢 -大家都有礼物吗?
Fred? George?
弗雷?看治?
-Hermione. -A Christmas toast.
-妙时 -来个圣诞数酒
To Mr. Harry Potter...
数哈利波特
...without whom I would not be here.
没有他“，我就不会在这里
-Harry.
-数哈利 -哈利
Harry.
哈利
That is delicious. I shall be needing some more of that.
太好喝了，再多个一点
Daddy, don't forget last Christmas.
别忘了去年的粮事
I can’t understand why you don't want to wear it, Ronald.
我搞不懂 你为什么不窜，沫思
l look like a bloody idiot, that’s why.
因为穿起来像白疯
No more than usual, Ron.
反正跟平常差不多
I don't know why....
你为什么不相信你妈的品味?
Nasty brat, standing there as bold as brass.
你这款小孩 厚颜无思地站在这里
Harry Potter, the boy who stopped the Dark Lord.
哈利波特 阻止黑魔王的男孩
Friend of Mudbloods and blood-traitors alike.
同时膛是麻种和叛乱的朋友
-lf my poor mistress only knew.... -Kreacher!
-如果被我可情的女主人知道… -怪角 !
That's enough of your bile. Away with you!
难约了没?快滚 !
Of course, master.
当然了，主人
Kreacher lives to serve the noble house of Black.
怪角生来就是要服侍 高足的布莱克家
Sorry about that.
不好意思
He never was very pleasant, even when I was a boy.
从我小时候 他就很没有礼狐
Not to me, anyway.
不过对我很好
What, you grew up here?
你在这守长大的吗?
This is my parents’ house.
这是我爸妈的房子
I offered it to Dumbledore as headquarters for the Order.
我提供给好不利多 当风凰会网部
About the only useful thing I've been able to do.
这大概是我唯一有用的地方
This is the Black family tree.
这是布莱克家的族谱
My deranged cousin.
我疯狂的堂妹
I hated the lot of them.
我好恨他们
My parents with their pure-blood mania.
我的父母只认可 血统纯正的巫师
My mother did that after I ran away.
我妈在我逃家和后弄成这样
Charming woman.
有趣的女人
I was 16.
那年我十六哉
Where did you go?
你去了哪里了
Round your dad's.
我去你爸那里
l was always welcome at the Potters’.
波特家随时都坎迎我
l see him so much in you, Harry.
我在你身上看到他，哈利
You are so very much alike.
你们两个真的太像了
I'm not so sure.
这我就不确定
Sirius, when I was....
天狼星，当我…
When I saw Mr. Weasley attacked, I wasn't just watching.
卫斯理先生被攻击时 我不只是旁秽而已
l was the snake.
我是那休蛇
And afterwards, in Dumbledore’s office...
和后来在如不利多办公室
...there was a moment when I wanted to--
有一箱那，我…我想…
This connection between me and Voldemort.
我跟伏地魔之问有联结
What if the reason for it is that 1 am becoming more like him?
我会不会变得跟他一样?
I just feel so angry all the time.
我无时乱刻都感到愤怒
And what if, after everything that I’ve been through...
当我经历过这些事情以后
...something’s gone wrong inside me? What if I'm becoming bad?
我会不会走上岔路? 最后变得很壤?
l want you to listen to me very carefully, Harry.
我要你仔细散我说，哈利
You're not a bad person.
你不是壤人
You're a very good person who bad things have happened to.
你是很好的人 只是碰到一些壤事
You understand?
你懂吗?
Besides, the world isn’t split into good people and Death Eaters.
涡且世界不是 只有好人跟食死人
We've all got both light and dark inside of us.
人的内心 同时有光明面跟黑暗面
What matters is the part we choose to act on.
差别在於我们想运用哪一面
That's who we really are.
那才是真正的我们
Harry, time to go.
哈利，该走了
When all this is over, we'll be a proper family.
这一切结束和后 我们就是一家人
You'll see.
等著上
Come on.
来吧
Really?
真的?
Harry. Harry.
哈利，哈利
Hagrid’s back.
海格回来了
I'm sorry.
对不起
I will say this one last time.
我再说最后一次
I'm ordering you to tell me where you've been.
我命令你告诉我 你去了哪里
Il told you. I've been away for me health.
我说过了“，我去休养身体
-Your health? -Yeah. Bit of fresh air, you know.
-体瘤身体 ? -没错，我需要新鲜空所
Oh, yes. As gamekeeper, fresh air must be difficult to come by.
是啊，身为养殖场管理人 大概很难呼吸到新鲜空气
If l were you, I shouldn't get too used to being back.
如果我是你 我不会指望符太久
In fact, ! mightn’t bother unpacking at all.
最好速行李都先别打开
Dumbledore sent me to parley with the giants.
如不利多 派我去找巨人合作
Giants?
巨人?
You found them?
你找到了吗?
Well, they're not that hard to find, to be perfectly honest. They’re so big, see?
老实说他们一点也不准找 他们埃标都很大
I tried to convince them to join the cause.
我努力说服他们加入我们
But I wasn’t the only one that was trying to win them over.
不过我不是唯一 想拉提他们的人
-Death Eaters? -Yes.
-还有食死人? -是的
Trying to persuade them to join You-Know-Who.
他们想说服互人 加入那个人
-Did they? -l gave them Dumbledore’s message.
-结果呢? -我传达如不利多的口信
Suppose some of them remember he was friendly to them. I suppose.
也许有人会记得 他兽对他们很好
And they did this to you?
他们分这样对你?
Not exactly, no.
也不算是他们啦
Oh, go on, you have it, then, you dozy dog.
来吧，给你吃，策狗狗
It’s changing out there.
外面改变很大
Just like last time.
就跟上次一样
There's a storm coming, Harry.
一场腥风血雨就要来临
We'd all best be ready when she does.
我们最好先做好准备
We have confirmed that 10 high-security prisoners...
我们确认了十个高度警戒因犯
...in the early hours of yesterday evening did escape.
〈阿兹卡班大逃亡 )
And of course, the Muggle prime minister has been alerted to the danger.
(山十欲来)
We strongly suspect...
我们强烈怀疑
...that the breakout was engineered...
这场大逃狱
...by a man with personal experience in escaping from Azkaban...
由曾经从阿兹卡班逃狱的人策划
..-notorious mass murderer Sirius Black...
黔名昭彰的凶手天狼星布莱克
...cousin of escapee Bellatrix Lestrange.
逃犯由拉雷斯壮的表哥
Dumbledore warned Fudge this could happen.
部不利多警告明夫子 这种事可能会发生
He’s gonna get us all killed just because he can't face the truth.
他不敢面对现实 害大家章瑞
Harry.
哈利
I wanted to apologize.
我…我想跟你道歉
Now even me mum says the Prophet's version of things don’t add up.
连我姻都说 《预言家日报》不可靠
So, what I’m really trying to say is that I believe you.
我想说的是… 我相信你
Neville?
奈威?
Fourteen years ago...
十四年前…
...a Death Eater named Bellatrix Lestrange...
一个叫中拉雷斯壮的食死人
...used a Cruciatus Curse on my parents.
对我爸杂使用酷刑吕
She tortured them for information...
她折磨他们 拷问他们
...but they never gave in.
但是我爸杂都没属服
I'm quite proud to be their son.
我很骑人向能当他们的儿子
But I’m not sure I'm ready for everyone to know just yet.
但我还没有化人备好 让大家知道
We're gonna make them proud, Neville. That's a promise.
我保证我们会让他们感到一例
Make it a powerful memory, the happiest you can remember.
想著让你感到坚强的回忆 最快乐的记居
Allow it to fill you up. Keep trying, Seamus.
让它充满你的心 继续试，西英
George, your turn now.
奋治，现在换你了
Expecto Patronum.
疾疾，访法现身
A full-bodied Patronus is the most difficult to produce...
要扔造完整形状的议法 很困难
...but shield forms can also be equally useful against a variety of opponents.
但是盾甲形状 也能对付各种散人
Wow, that was really good.
好属害哦
Fantastic, Ginny.
很好，金妮
Just remember, your Patronus can only protect you for as long as you stay focused.
记住，只要专注於访法 就能保护你
So focus, Luna.
保持专注，露娜
Think of the happiest thing you can.
想想最快乐的回忆
Expecto Patronum.
疾疾，访法现身
-I'm trying. -l know. It’s good.
-我在努力 -我知道，很好
This is really advanced stuff, guys. You're doing so well.
这是很高附的魔法 大家都很棒
Expecto Patronum.
疾疾，访法现身
Pll make short work of this.
我来名大家省省事
Bombarda Maxima.
大爆爆
Get them.
拆住他们
Been watching them for weeks.
我难视他们很久了
And see, "Dumbledore’s Army”...
你看，“必不利多的军队
...proof of what I've been telling you tight from the beginning, Cornelius.
这证明我一开始 就跟你讲的事情
All your fear-mongering about You-Know-Who...
你一直在散播诡言 说那个人要回来
...-never fooled us for a minute.
驴不了我们的
We saw your lies for what they were:
我们看穿了你的议言
A smokescreen for your bid to seize control of the Ministry.
你为了掌控魔法部 放出的凿幕弹
Naturally.
没错
No, professor. He had nothing to do with it. It was me.
不，教授 伍他无关，主使是我
Most noble of you, Harry, to shield me, but as has been pointed out...
你捍卫我的情操很高贵 但是事实很明显
...the parchment clearly says “Dumbledore’s Army," not "Potter's."
上面写的是“性不利多的军队” 不是“波特的军队
l instructed Harry to form this organization.
我指示哈利成立这个组织
And I, and I alone, am responsible for its activities.
我顾意为这些行为负起全责
Dispatch an owl to the Daily Prophet.
派和猎头魔送信给《预言家日报》
If we hurry, we should still make the morning edition.
也许能超上明早出刊
Dawlish, Shacklebolt, you will escort Dumbledore...
钝力、侠钧 押解如不利多…
...to Azkaban...
到阿兹卡班
...to await trial for conspiracy and sedition.
等待除谋叛乱界的审判
I thought we might hit this little snag.
事情丽怕没这度顺利
You seem to be laboring under the delusion that I’m going to--
你们似乎误以为我会…
What was the phrase?
怎庆说呢?
--come quietly.
东手就的
Well, I can tell you this:
不过我告诉你们
I have no intention of going to Azkaban.
我完全扰意去阿兹卡班
Enough of this.
说钓了吧
Take him.
立刻押走
Well, you may not like him, minister...
部长，你牙然不喜欢他
...but you can't deny...
不过不能和认
...Dumbledore has got style.
好不利多很有格调
Boys and girls are not permitted to be within eight inches of each other.
男女学生之问 必须保持入黄叶的距离
Those wishing to join the inquisitorial Squad for extra credit....
学生想加入督察小组 以来加分…
Students will be submitted to questioning about suspected illicit activities.
疑似从事不法活动者 需接爱质询
Any student in noncompliance will be expelled.
拒绝合作的学生将被开除
Harry.
哈利
You did everything you could. No one could win against that old hag.
你慢力了 没人对付得了老巫婆
Even Dumbledore didn’t see this coming.
就连必不利多也没料到
Harry, if it's anyone’s fault, it’s ours.
就算有错，也是我们的错
Yeah, we talked you into it.
是我们说服你这广做的
Yeah, but I agreed.
可是我也同意了
I tried so hard to help, and all it’s done is make things worse.
我很努力想要帮忙 邹只让情况伙得更煤
Anyway, that doesn’t matter anymore.
反正这些都不重要了
Because I don't want to play anymore. All it does is make you care too much.
我不玩了 继续下去只会让你太在平
And the more you care, the more you have to lose.
就必须失去念多
-So maybe it’s just better to.... -To what?
-所以我们最好… -最好怎样?
To go it alone.
管好自己就好
Hagrid.
海格
Any idea where he’s taking us?
他要带我们去哪里?
Hagrid, why can’t you just tell us?
海格，你干嘛不直接说?
I've never seen the centaurs so riled.
我没有看人轧这麻激支
And they're dangerous at the best of times.
凶们正常的时候 就约危险了
The Ministry restricts their territory much more...
魔法部继续限制籽们的地妈
... they'll have a full uprising on their hands.
名们就要起来暴动了
Hagrid, what's going on?
到底是怎庆回事?
I'm sorry to be so mysterious, you three.
抱歉要搞得这广神秘分分
I wouldn't be bothering you at all with it, but with Dumbledore gone...
我也不想烦你们 不过部不利多不在了
.. [Il likely be getting the sack any day now.
我也随时可能会被开除
And I just couldn't leave without telling someone about him.
我不能没说出他的事就走掉
Grawpy.
啤啦
Down here, you great buffoon.
我在下面，你这小傻瓜
Brought you some company.
我带朋友来找你
I couldn't just leave him, because--
我不能丢下他不管
Blimey.
老天答
Well, half brother, really.
其实是不同爸爸
He’s completely harmless, just like I said. Little high-spirited, is all.
他不会伤害任何人 只是有一点遇支
-Grawpy, that is not polite. -Hagrid, do something.
-小啤啦，这样很没礼貌 -海格，快想闪法
We talked about this. You do not grab, do you?
我跟你说过，不准抓人
That's your new friend, Hermione.
她是你的新朋友妙果
Grawpy.
啤啦
Put me down.
把我放下来
Now.
快点
You all right?
你没事吧?
Fine.
没事
Just needs a firm hand, is all.
他只是需要赤格管教
I think you've got an admirer.
你多了一个仰幕者
You just stay away from her, all right?
准好下一点，册到没?
He gets his own food and all.
他自己会找东西吃
It's company he'll be needing when I'm gone.
我不在时 他需要人陪伴
You will look after him, won't you?
你们会照刁他，对吧?
I'm the only family he’s got.
我是他唯一的亲人
Feeling sentimental?
觉得很伤感吗 ?
-That’s private. -Not to me.
-这是我的隐私 -执不住我的
And not to the Dark Lord, if you don't improve.
你不进步的话 也抽不住黑魔王
Every memory he has access to is a weapon he can use against you.
你的回居 都是他对付你的利器
You won't last two seconds if he invades your mind.
被他入侵绝对挝不了两秒
You're just like your father.
你就跟你爸一样
Lazy, arrogant.
懒情又自大
-Don’t say a word against my father. -Weak.
-不准说我爸的坏话 ! -软弱
-I’m not weak. -Then prove it.
-我才不坎弱 ! -那就证明给我看
Control your emotions.
控制你的情绪
Discipline your mind.
训练你的心智
Legilimens.
破破心
Harry.
哈利
Sirius.
天狼星
fi may vomit.
我快呈了
Stop it.
快住手
Is this what you call control?
这就是你所谓的控制力吗?
We've been at it for hours. If I could just rest.
我们张好久了，我需要休息
The Dark Lord isn't resting.
黑魔王从不休息
You and Black, you're two of a kind.
你和天狼星还真像
Sentimental children forever whining about how bitterly unfair your lives have been.
像多悉善感的小孩子一样 一直抱怒人生痛苦又不公平
Well, it may have escaped your notice, but life isn’t fair.
你要搞清楚 人生本来就不公平
Your blessed father knew that. In fact, he frequently saw to it.
你老爸也知道 事实上，他对我就很不公平
-My father was a great man. -Your father was a swine.
-我父亲是个伟大的人 -你爸是下三每
-Legilimens. -Protego.
一破破心 -破心议
Come on, Moony, Padfoot.
拜旗，月影，软足
Snape. Expelliarmus.
石内卜
-Dad. -impedimenta.
-和爸 -喷喷障
Snivellus Greasy.
鼻涕卜，咯分分…
Right. Who wants to see me take off Snivelly’s trousers?
有没有人想看 我帮鼻涕卜辽神子?
Snivellus Greasy.
鼻涕卜，咯分分…
Enough.
金了
Your lessons are at an end.
你这堂课已经结束了
-What's your name? -Michael.
-你叫什么名字? -故可
Your hand’s gonna be fine, Michael.
不要准过好不好
Yeah. It’s not as bad as it seems. See?
其实没有看起来那订严重
It’s fading already.
你看，我的消了
You can hardly see ours anymore, and the pain stops after a while.
对啊，你看我的也消了 过一阵子就不会痛了
As I told you once before, Mr. Potter...
我之前已经说通了，波特
. naughty children deserve to be punished.
顽皮的学生就应该得到俭昼
You know, George...
你知道吗，和在治
...[’ve always felt our futures lay outside the world of academic achievement.
我一直赏得我们的未来在外面 而不是在学校里面
Fred, I've been thinking exactly the same thing.
弗雷，我想的跟你一模一样
All right, professor!
好耶，教授 !
Here you go.
开始唆
Ready when you are.
好了跟我说一声
I need that prophecy.
我需要那个预言
You'll have to kill me.
你毅了我再说
Oh, I will. But first, you will fetch it for me.
我会的 不过你得先去帮有我拿来
Crucio.
加咒虚 !
Sirius.
天狼星
Harry, are you sure?
哈利，你确定邑 ?9
Il saw it. It’s just like with Mr. Weasley.
我看到了 就像我看到卫斯理先生
It’s the door I’ve been dreaming about.
那是我最近一直枕到的门
I couldn’t remember where I'd seen it before.
只是我想不起来在哪里看角
Sirius said Voldemort was after something.
天狼星说伏地魔想找什么东西
Something he didn’t have the last time, in the Department of Mysteries.
他上次没找到的东西 东西就在神秘部门里头
Harry, please, just listen.
哈利，拜斌，贡我说
What if Voldemort meant for you to see this?
如果伏地魔是故意 让你看到的话，怎和办?
What if he’s only hurting Sirius because he’s trying to get to you?
如果他想利用伤害天狼星 来抓你怎庆办?
What if he is? I'm supposed to just let him die?
如果是真的 我就该让天狼星死?
Hermione, he’s the only family I’ve got left.
妙肝，他是我现在唯一的疯人
What do we do?
我们该怎么办?
We'll have to use the Floo Network.
用呼噬网超过去
Umbridge has the chimneys under surveillance.
思不里居监视所有的粳
Not all of them.
她自己的就没有
Alohomora.
阿咯哈姆啦
Alert the Order if you can.
你们去警告风凰会
-Are you mental? We're going with you. -It’s too dangerous.
-你疯了吗 ? 我们也要去 -这太危险了
When are you going to get it into your head? We're in this together.
你到底什么时候才会晾解? 我们大家是一体的
That you are.
你说的一点都没错
Caught this one trying to help the Weasley girl.
这小子想帮本斯理家的女孩
You were going to Dumbledore, weren't you?
你要去找几不利多 对不对?
-No. -Liar.
-不对 一骗子
-You sent for me, headmistress? -Snape, yes.
-虹找我吗 ' 校藤? -没错，石内卜
The time has come for answers, whether he wants to give them to me or not.
不管他想不想说
Have you brought the Veritaserum?
你的吐真剂带来了吗 ?
I'm afraid you've used up all my stores interrogating students.
你询问学生时 把我的库存用完了
The last of it on Miss Chang.
最后一次是用在张秋身上
Unless you wish to poison him--
如果是想毒死他 那没问题
And I assure you, I would have the greatest sympathy if you did.
我到时候一定会很同情他
--l cannot help you.
但是我没有吐真剂
He’s got Padfoot.
他抓了软足
He’s got Padfoot at the place where it’s hidden.
他在藏东西的地方 把软足抓走
Padfoot? What is Padfoot? Where what is hidden?
葡足? 什么是软足? 藏什么东西 ?
What is he talking about, Snape?
怎订回事 ? 他在说些什么 ?
No idea.
我哪知道?
Very well.
好吧
You give me no choice, Potter.
你让我别扰选择，波特
As this is an issue of Ministry security...
这件事关侨著魔法部的安全
...you leave me with...
你让我没有…
..no alternative.
选择的余地
The Cruciatus Curse ought to loosen your tongue.
酷刑咒谭该可以让你说实话
That's illegal.
那是这法的
What Cornelius doesn't know won't hurt him.
只要别让夫子知道就没问题
Tell her, Harry!
快告诉她，哈利!
Tell me what?
告诉我什么?
Well, if you won't tell her where it is...
你不告诉她在哪里…
- el will,
那我告诉她
Where what is?
什么东西? 在哪里?
Dumbledore’s secret weapon.
部不利多的秘密武器
How much further?
还有多速?
Not far.
不天了
It had to be somewhere students wouldn't find it accidentally.
东西得藏在 不会被学生撞见的地方
What are you doing?
你想干嘛?
Improvising.
随机谭伙
Well?
怎庆样 ?
Where is this weapon?
这个武器在哪里?
There isn't one, is there?
根本没有武器，对不对?了
You were trying to trick me.
你只是想要我
You know...
知道吧…
...L really hate children.
我最讨厌小孩子
You have no business here, centaur. This is a Ministry matter.
这里没有你们的事情，人忆 这是魔法部的事情
Lower your weapons.
放下你们的武器
I warn you, under the law, as creatures of near-human intelligence....
我警告你们 法律规定，智慧不如人类的生物…
Protego.
破心访
How dare you?
好大的脆子
incarcerous.
名继禁
Please. Please stop it. Please.
拜旗 ! 快住手 ! 拜旗!
Now, enough. I will have order.
现在开始 你们给我规扯一点
You filthy animal.
你们人这些畜和性
Do you know who I am?
知道我是谁吗?
Leave him alone. It’s not his fault.
不要这样对他 这不是他的错
No, he doesn’t understand.
不要，他什么都不懂
Potter, do something. Tell them I mean no harm.
快想办法告诉他们 我不是故意要伤害他们
I'm sorry, professor.
抱娄，教授
But I must not tell lies.
我不可以说议
What are you doing?
你们在干什么?
lam Senior Undersecretary Dolores Jane Umbridge.
我是魔法部政务次长 桃乐思恩不里居
Let me go!
放天我 !
Thank you, Grawp.
谢谢你，听啦
Hermione. Hermione, Sirius.
妙肝，妙杂，天狼星
-How’'d you get away? -Puking Pastilles. It wasn't pretty.
-你们是怎庆逃出来的? -利用旺旺糖，膛满吗心的
Told them I was hungry, wanted some sweets.
我说我肚子饿了起吃糖果
They told me to bugger off and ate the lot themselves.
他们叫我列作劳 然后抢去吃掉
That was clever, Ron.
这招很隐明，荣思
-Has been known to happen. -It was brilliant.
-我只是展现实力 -这招太妙了
So how are we getting to London?
我们怎庆去伦敦?
Look, it’s not that 1 don’t appreciate everything you've done, all of you...
我很感激你们大家 为我做的这些事
...but I've got you into enough trouble as it is.
但我已经蔚你们 惹了不少麻烦
Dumbledore’s Army's supposed to be about doing something real.
如不利多的军队 谭该开始玩真的了
Or was that all just words to you?
难道你不遵守诺言吗?
Maybe you don't have to do this all by yourself, mate.
你根本就不需要孤军奢喜
So how are we going to get to London?
那我们应该怎么去伦敦?
We fly, of course.
当然是用丧的啊
Department of Mysteries.
神秘部门
This is it.
神秘部门到了
Ninety-two. Ninety-three.
九十二、九十三
Ninety-four.
九十四
Ninety-five.
九十五
-He should be here. -Harry.
-他麻该在这壬 -哈利
It’s got your name on it.
这上面有你的名字
The one with the power to vanquish the Dark Lord approaches.
拉有消减黑魔王力量的人 即将降酰
And the Dark Lord shall mark him as his equal...
黑魔王将标记他为已之同等
...but he shall have power the Dark Lord knows not.
但他搓有黑魔王未知的力量
For neither can live while the other survives.
十者之中必有一人 死於另一人之手
Harry.
哈利
Where's Sirius?
天狼星在哪儿?
You know, you really should learn to tell the difference between dreams...
你应该学习分辨欧境…
...and reality.
还有真实
You saw only what the Dark Lord wanted you to see.
你看到的 只是黑魔王安排的部面
Now, hand me the prophecy.
把预言交给我吧
If you do anything to us, I'll break it.
你敢支手我就把它打破
He knows how to play.
他知道游戏规则呢
Itty, bitty baby.
可过的小实具
Potter.
波特
Bellatrix Lestrange.
内拉雷斯壮
Neville Longbottom, is it? How's Mum and Dad?
泰威隆巴屯 爸妈还好吧?
Better, now they're about to be avenged.
好多了 有人要帮他们报仇了
Now, let's everybody just calm down...
大家先冷静一下
... shall we?
好吗?
All we want is that prophecy.
我们要的只是预言而已
Why did Voldemort need me to come and get this?
伏地魔为什么 要我来拿这东西?
You dare speak his name?
你竟敢直呼他的名字
You filthy half-blood!
你这蚊岁的混血 !
It’s all right. He’s just a curious lad, aren't you?
没关像，他只不过是好奇实实
Prophecies can only be retrieved by those about whom they are made.
只有超预言有关的人 才能拿到预言
Which is lucky for you, really.
这是你走运的地方，真的
Haven't you always wondered...
你交道从来没有想过
...what was the reason for the connection between you and the Dark Lord?
为什么你跟黑魔王一直有联结?
Why he was unable to kill you...
为什么你是届儿时候
...when you were just an infant?
他欠不掉你?
Don't you want to know the secret of your scar?
你不想知道 你头上疤痕的秘密吧?9
All the answers are there, Potter, in your hand.
所有的答案 都在你手祷，波特
All you have to do...
你只要…
.. is give it to me.
把它交给我
Then I can show you everything.
我自然会告诉你一切
I've waited 14 years.
我已经等了十四年
I know.
我知道
I guess I can wait a little longer. Now. Stupefy.
再多等一下也扰所谓 上，吊唱失!
Stupefy.
吊唱失!
Levicorpus.
个个吊
Petrificus Totalus.
整整石化
Well done, Neville.
做得好，奈威
Stupefy.
吊唱失!
-Stupefy.
-虽吊失!
Reducto.
嗓嗓消!
Get back to the door.
快跑去门口
Department of Mysteries. They got that bit right, didn’t they?
神秘部门 这地方果然很施恰
The voices.
有静音
Can you tell what they’re saying?
区得出来说什么吗?
There aren't any voices, Harry.
根本没声音，哈利
Let’s get out of here.
我们快玲并
I hear them too.
我也匠到了
Harry, it’s just an empty archway.
哈利，那只是 一休空走道而已
Please, Harry.
拜旗，哈利
Get behind me.
快到我后面 !
Did you actually believe...
你逮真的相信
...or were you truly naive enough to think...
你真的天真到以为
...that children stood a chance against us?
你们人这些小孩能打败我们吗 ?
I'll make this simple for you, Potter.
我给你一个简单的选择，波特
Give me the prophecy now...
现在就把预言给我
..-or watch your friends die.
不然就看著你的朋友死
Don't give it to him, Harry.
不要给他，哈利
Get away from my godson.
不要碰我的教子
Now, listen to me. Take the others and get out of here.
聘我说，我要你 带其他人疮并
What? No, I'm staying with you.
不行，我要跟你在一起
You've done beautifully.
哈利，你表现得很棒
Now, let me take it from here.
接下来就交给我吧
Black.
布莱克
Expelliarmus!
去去，武器走!
Nice one, James.
表现不错，小麻姆
Avada Kedavra.
阿哇咀喀咀啦
No. No.
不!
I killed Sirius Black.
我儿了天狼星
-You coming to get me? -Crucio.
-快来啊 -咒思虚
You've got to mean it, Harry.
施响语要认真，哈利
She killed him. She deserves it.
她角了天狼星，她该死
You know the spell, Harry.
你知道那咒语，哈利
Do it.
快点
So weak.
真是软弱
It was foolish of you to come here tonight, Tom.
你真电蠢 玩择今晚来这里，混姆
The Aurors are on their way.
正气师都超来了
By which time I shall be gone, and you...
等他们到天时 我已经走了，而你…
... shall be dead.
也已经死了
You've lost, old man.
你翰了“，老头
Harry.
哈利
So weak.
真是软弱
So vulnerable.
不堪一击
Look at me.
看著我
Harry, it isn’t how you are alike.
哈利，你不是这样的人
It's how you are not.
你不是这种人
Harry?
哈利
You're the weak one...
你才是款弱的人
..-and you'll never know love or friendship.
你 永焉 不 懂 什么是党跟友情
And I feel sorry for you.
我为你感到悲哀
You're a fool, Harry Potter.
你真是思春，哈利波特
And you will lose everything.
你将会失去所有的一切
He’s back.
他回来了
I know how you feel, Harry.
我上解你的感受，哈利
No, you don't.
你不影解
It's my fault.
全都是我的错
No, the fault is mine.
不对，是我的错
I knew it was only a matter of time...
我知道伏地魔辟早会知道
...before Voldemort made the connection between you.
他跟你之问的联瑞
I thought by distancing myself from you, as I have done all year...
我以为只要跟你保持距离 就像这一整年
...he’d be less tempted, and therefore you might be more protected.
他就不会想掌控你 你也比较能得到保护
The prophecy said:
预言说
“Neither one can live while the other one survives.”
“十者之中必有一人 死於另一人之手^
It means one of us is gonna have to kill the other, in the end.
表示有一个人 最后要角死对方
Yes.
对
Why didn't you tell me?
你为什么不告诉我?
For the same reason you tried to save Sirius.
跟你想救天狼星的原因一样
The same reason your friends saved you.
跟你朋友救你的原因一样
After all these years, after all you've suffered...
经过这些年 你经历了这刻多折麻
...[ didn’t want to cause you . any more pain.
我不想再加重你的痛苦
l cared too much about you.
因为我太关心你了
How come you're not at the feast?
你怎订没有参加宴会?
Lost all my possessions. Apparently people have been hiding them.
我的东西全都不见了 谭该又是被其他人藏起来了
That's awful.
真是通分
Oh, it’s all good fun.
其实还车好玩的
But as it’s the last night, l really do need them back.
不过明天要回家 我得快找回来
Do you want any help finding them?
需要我旭你找邑?
I'm sorry about your godfather, Harry.
我为你教父的事感到准过
Are you sure you don't want any help looking?
确定不需要我帮忙吗?
That's all right.
没关侨啦
Anyway, my mum always said...
反正我杂妈总是说…
...the things we lose have a way of coming back to us in the end.
失去的最后都能回到我们身录
If not always in the way we expect.
引然不见得是我们期待的方式
Think I'll just go have some pudding.
我还是去吃一点布丁好了
I've been thinking about something Dumbledore said to me.
我一直在想 好不利多跟我说的事
What's that?
什么事?
That even though we've got a fight ahead of us...
路然我们必须面对一场战同
...we've got one thing that Voldemort doesn’t have.
但是我们拉有 伏地魔没有的东西
Yeah?
是什么?
Something worth fighting for.
值得我们捍卫的一切
[ENGLISH]
[MANDARIN - R3]